<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bugra Alkan | ISI Research Lab</title><link>https://isilablsbu.github.io/IndustrialSystemIntelligence/author/bugra-alkan/</link><atom:link href="https://isilablsbu.github.io/IndustrialSystemIntelligence/author/bugra-alkan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Bugra Alkan</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://isilablsbu.github.io/IndustrialSystemIntelligence/author/bugra-alkan/avatar_hu_ad28ddc879d0bda5.jpg</url><title>Bugra Alkan</title><link>https://isilablsbu.github.io/IndustrialSystemIntelligence/author/bugra-alkan/</link></image><item><title>Bugra Alkan</title><link>https://isilablsbu.github.io/IndustrialSystemIntelligence/author/bugra-alkan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isilablsbu.github.io/IndustrialSystemIntelligence/author/bugra-alkan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Bugra Alkan is a senior lecturer at the Computer Science and Informatics Division, London South Bank University, carrying out research and teaching activities in the fields of artificial intelligence, cyber-physical systems, and industrial robotics. Prior to joining LSBU, I was a post-doctoral researcher with the Computer Science Department at the University of Bristol and a research fellow at WMG (Warwick Manufacturing Group), the University of Warwick, U.K. I received my Ph.D. degree in engineering from WMG, University of Warwick, Coventry, U.K., in 2019, specialising in cyber-physical industrial automation systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Bugra Alkan holds a PhD in Engineering from Warwick Manufacturing Group (WMG), University of Warwick, where he specialised in cyber-physical industrial automation. He is currently a Senior Lecturer in Artificial Intelligence and Robotics at the School of Computer Science and Digital Technologies, within the College of Technology and Environment at London South Bank University (LSBU). Prior to this, he was a Postdoctoral Research Associate in Computer Science at the University of Bristol, contributing to interdisciplinary projects at the intersection of systems engineering and smart autonomous systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Alkan’s academic background spans mechanical engineering, manufacturing systems, and computational intelligence. His research focuses on the convergence of smart manufacturing, industrial artificial intelligence, industrial robotics, and human–robot collaboration. He has significant experience in data-driven decision-making, cyber-physical systems, and digital twins, and is actively engaged in developing intelligent solutions for real-world manufacturing challenges. He has led and collaborated on numerous research initiatives funded by major organisations including the Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council (EPSRC), Innovate UK, the Royal Society, EU Horizon, and various industry partners, securing an institutional share of over £670k as Principal Investigator (PI) and Co-Investigator (Co-I). Dr. Alkan has authored more than 40 peer-reviewed publications (h-index: 16, i10-index: 21) in leading international journals and conferences, and regularly serves as a reviewer for high-impact venues. His work has been recognised with several Best Paper Awards, including one from the prestigious CIRP CATS in Gothenburg (2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At LSBU, Dr. Alkan teaches at both undergraduate and postgraduate levels, where he leads and coordinates modules on artificial intelligence and industrial cyber-physical systems. He is a Fellow of the Higher Education Academy (FHEA). Beyond academia, he maintains close collaborations with industry, aiming to bridge the gap between research innovation and practical application. He currently serves as an Associate Editor for two SCI-indexed journals: Heliyon (Mechanical Engineering section) and Industrial Robot: The International Journal of Robotics Research and Application.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gest-SAR: A Gesture-Controlled Spatial AR System for Interactive Manual Assembly Guidance with Real-Time Operational Feedback</title><link>https://isilablsbu.github.io/IndustrialSystemIntelligence/publication/journal-article/journal1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isilablsbu.github.io/IndustrialSystemIntelligence/publication/journal-article/journal1/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-note"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="alert alert-note"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the publication&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;full text&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;supplementary notes&lt;/strong&gt; here. You can use rich formatting such as including &lt;a href="https://docs.hugoblox.com/content/writing-markdown-latex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>State of the art and future directions of digital twin-enabled smart assembly automation in discrete manufacturing industries</title><link>https://isilablsbu.github.io/IndustrialSystemIntelligence/publication/journal-article/journal2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isilablsbu.github.io/IndustrialSystemIntelligence/publication/journal-article/journal2/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-note"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="alert alert-note"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the publication&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;full text&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;supplementary notes&lt;/strong&gt; here. You can use rich formatting such as including &lt;a href="https://docs.hugoblox.com/content/writing-markdown-latex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>